<tool id="rename_atoms" name="Rename atoms" version="1.0.0">
    <description>of a PDB file according to GROMACS.</description>
    <command interpreter="python">

        rename_atoms_pdb.py
          -i "$input_pdb"
          -n "${input_pdb.name}"
          -f "$force_field"
          -o "$new_pdb"
          -d "$new_pdb.files_path"
          -r "$__root_dir__"

    </command>
    <inputs>
        <param name="input_pdb" type="data" multiple="false" format="pdb" label="PDB File" />
        <param name="force_field" type="select" label="Force field" help="">
            <option value="amber99sb-ildn">AMBER99</option>
            <option value="charmm27">CHARMM27</option>
        </param>

    </inputs>
    <outputs>
        <data name="new_pdb" format="pdb" label="${input_pdb.name}.atomrenamed.pdb"/>
    </outputs>
    <help>

.. class:: warningmark

This tool requires *PDB* format.

-----

::

    PDB files often use inconsistent nomenclature, and the selected force fields themselves are even worse.
    Note, in general, that residue nomenclature can be found in the force field's .rtp files,
    so the tool can check what names need to be supplied in the input coordinate file.

::

    The availables force fields in this tool are:

        - CHARMM27
        - AMBER99

        The residue nomenclature of the PDB file will be checked using these force field's .rtp files.

::

    The rtp file extension stands for residue toplogy.
    Such a file is needed by pdb2gmx to make a GROMACS topology for a protein contained in a .pdb file.
    The file contains the default interaction type for the 4 bonded interactions and residue entries,
    which consist of atoms and optionally bonds, angles dihedrals and impropers.

::

    If the input PDB file has a problem with the atom U nomenclature, the GROMACS program will output:

        "Fatal error:
        Residue 'U' not found in residue topology database"

    This tool checks the atoms nomenclature on the PDB file with the GROMACS residues database and
    replace by the corresponding atom name.

::

    The output of this tool will be the PDB file with all the necessary atoms renamed.

    </help>
    <citations>
        <citation type="doi">10.1002/jcc.20291</citation>
    </citations>
</tool>
